### SUMMARY OF SKILLS

Programming knowledge in C, C#, C++, Java, Python, Perl, SQL, MongoDB, HTML, JavaScript, LISP, Prolog, PHP and R

Experienced in working with **Rosetta** protein modeling suite Experienced in working in **GxP**, and **FDA** regulated environments

Experienced in working with **Git**, **SVN**, and **Mercurial** version control systems

Experienced in working with **Git, 5VN,** and **Wiercunal** version control systems

Effective presenter, communicator, writer, and public speaker Efficient at coordinating across multiple groups for requirements

Strong independent and autodidactic worker

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Ramapo College of New Jersey - Mahwah, NJ

Bachelor of Science: Bioinformatics, May 2016, *Magna cum laude* Bachelor of Science: Computer Science, May 2016, *Magna cum laude* 

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Pfizer Inc. - Pearl River, NY

Manager, Informatics/Engineering, Research Informatics, Sep 2021– Current Senior System Analyst, Research Informatics, Dec 2018– Sep 2021

System Analyst, Research Informatics, Jan 2017 - Dec 2018

Support Vaccines R&D laboratories by through developing, supporting, and validating applications

- Develop and design systems to manage, analyze, and report laboratory data in our Laboratory Information Management System (LIMS)
- Create and provide ad hoc reports in Oracle Database using SQL
- Perform benchmarks on system performance and follow up to optimize problematic processes
- Design and create tools to visualize and prioritize the Research Informatics support ticket queue using Java and JavaScript, with rapid prototyping using PHP
- Coordinating multiple laboratory groups to gather requirements for new assay systems
- Provide end user support for clients using Research Informatics systems
- Validate and document newly deployed/changed/upgraded systems and environments
- Manage projects and requirements using Jira
- Integrated data systems with Salesforce instance.

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# A Bioinformatic Approach to Investigate a Relationship between Cis-Regulatory U-Rich and G-quadruplex Motifs Involved in Mammalian Polyadenylation

School of Theoretical and Applied Sciences – Ramapo College of New Jersey Undergraduate Researcher, Jan. 2014 – July 2016

Developed genome-wide analysis tools using Java, JavaScript, C++, and Python

- Web service with a C++ backend and Python database access, on a Node.js webserver
- Performed programmatic alignments of sequence data using Needleman-Wunsch algorithm
- Extracted and stored nucleic acid sequence data and annotations using MongoDB

#### Marburg Virus Antibody Modeling using Comparative Modeling

Center for Structural Biology – Vanderbilt University & RosettaCommons Developer of Rosetta, powerful macromolecule structure prediction and design software

Research Intern, May. 2015 - Aug. 2015

NSF funded research internship through RosettaCommons

- Trained to understand Rosetta protein modeling suite and develop algorithms for protein folding
- Developed a protocol for efficient large scale comparative modeling of antibodies
- Accesses underlying Rosetta C++functions for modeling, XML for input of user parameters
- Integration with PyMOL using Python
- Increased automation using Perl and Bash scripts
- Benchmarked the efficacy of comparative modeling techniques